# ARTEM RYBLOV

+7(952) 44-98-154

ryblovartem@gmail.com  $\diamond$  LinkedIn  $\diamond$  GitHub

#### **ABOUT**

I'm a skilled Data Scientist with more than 4 years of experience in data science. I've helped companies optimize their current AI solutions and implement new ones.

I get excited about new opportunities where I can apply my skills to create solutions that help businesses achieve their goals and improve the lives of end users.

#### **SKILLS**

**Programming** Python, SQL

DS Frameworks Pandas, PySpark, NumPy/SciPy, Matplotlib/Seaborn, BeautifulSoup, Loguru

ML/DL/NLP Frameworks Scikit-learn, Catboost/XGBoost/LightGBM, Optuna, PyTorch,

Hugging Face, Sentence Transformers, NLTK, Gensim, Spacy

Tools/Platforms Git, Docker, Jira

#### EXPERIENCE

Data Scientist
OneFactor

Jul 2022 - Present
Remote

- Using telecom data did:
  - 3x Credit Scoring models
  - 1x Anti-fraud model
  - 3x Lead Generation models
  - 5x AutoML models
  - 6x Geoanalytics reports
  - 8x Ad-hoc tasks
- Using the principles of clean code:
  - Refactored >15 jupyter notebooks
  - Transformed set of raw notebooks into Geoanalytics framework
- Implemented AB testing for model comparison using McNemar test

## NLP Engineer HARMAN

May 2019 - Feb 2022 Nizhny Novgorod, Russia

• Developed an end-to-end Offline NLP framework for training and testing Intent/Token Classification (NER) models for mobile devices (tf-lite), which was successfully applied for two customers in 2021.

- Implemented semantic search approach (pretrained embeddings + approximate nearest neighbours) for intent classification that significantly improved the quality of predictions, training & inference time, and was accepted in production as the main intent classifier for voice assistant.
- Led the NLP team and took part in road-map planning, defining the main directions of development and detailing them.
- Took part in the development of personal cruise assistant MSC Zoe (NLP):
  - Developed Noise Sentences Classifier to filter out truncated sentences which improved UX;

- Enhanced Entity Linking with Similarity Algorithm based on the Levenshtein distance which led to better recognition of named entities.

#### **PROJECTS**

## Shows Analysis

I've scraped information about top-1000 movies and top-1000 series, and started investigation.

- Parsing web-pages
- Data Analytics:
  - Research on the quality of localization of movie titles
- Data Science
  - Sentiment Analysis of Show Reviews

### Small Projects

- Churn Prediction | Binary Classification, EDA, Catboost + Optuna
- Salary prediction | Regression, DL, NLP, EDA, PyTorch
- Simpsons classification | Multiclass classification, DL, CV, Transfer Learning, PyTorch

#### **EDUCATION**

Master of Economics, Higher School of Economics	2016 - 2018
Cum. GPA: 9.0 / 10.0	
Bachelor of Computer Science, State University of Nizhny Novgorod	2012 - 2016

Cum. GPA:  $4.5\ /\ 5.0$ 

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

- Comparison of Machine Learning Methods for Analysis of Ulcerative Colitis Proteomic Data
- Parenclitic Network Analysis of Methylation Data for Cancer Identification